Alexander Hurtado

Sioux Falls, South Dakota, United States



Alex_Hurtado96@outlook.com



linkedin.com/in/alexander-hurtado-5727631a1

Summary

Upcoming Southeast Technical College graduate offering a strong foundation in software engineering and programming principles across multiple platforms.

Experience in object-oriented programming; developing, testing, and debugging code; designing interfaces; and administering systems and networks.

Quickly learn and master new technologies; successful working in both team and self-directed settings.

Experience

Group Lead

MSA - The Safety Company

Sep 2020 - Oct 2020 (2 months)

Develop and execute production plan by scheduling/assigning associates across 3 shifts. Establish priorities and track progress.

Revise schedules as needed and resolve problems in meeting the plan.

Meet with Supply Chain staff daily to discuss issues such as material shortages and customer demand.

Make adjustments appropriately.

Prepare annual department budget and monitor results on a monthly basis.

Manage job-closeout variances.

Work with all plant support groups i.e. Safety, Industrial, Manufacturing, Test & Quality Engineering groups as required.

Drive execution of Safety 24/7, Continuous Improvement and Customer Satisfaction initiatives.

Lead and promote use of, and ensure compliance to the MSA Operating System.

Manage equipment problems in department and make sure repairs are completed in a timely manner.

Participate in continuous improvement projects to enhance delivery, cost and quality for the Final Assembly department.

Quality Assurance Representative

United States Marine Corps

Jun 2018 - Sep 2020 (2 years 4 months)

Quality Assurance Representative that adheres to policies and procedures to prevent any occurrence of defects. experience in the avionics field with various Type Model Series aircraft. A competent, reliable, and committed professional with a proven record of success while constantly assuming increased levels of responsibility to reach any organizational goals, on-time.

Aviation Electronic Technician

United States Marine Corps

Jun 2012 - Sep 2020 (8 years 4 months)

Electronic Micro-Miniature/Instrument repair technician at an intermediate (component level electronics) maintenance and repair facility. Responsible for inspecting, testing, and repairing of aeronautical modules, circuit cards, electrical harnesses, instruments and other electronic components utilized on military aircraft and support equipment obtained a completed apprenticeship through the United Services Military Apprenticeship Program, with over 8,000 hours of On The Job training (OJT) and documentation.

Education



Southeast Tech

Computer programming, Computer and Information Sciences and Support Services Aug 2021 - May 2023



Coastal Carolina Community College

Computer Programming Jan 2021 - May 2021



Northern Virginia Community College

Aeronautics/Aviation/Aerospace Science and Technology, General Jan 2016 - May 2016

Licenses & Certifications



Electric Mechanic - U.S. Department of Labor

509116

Skills

Operations Management • Analytical Skills • Team Coordination • C# • MySQL • Java • PHP • JavaScript • HTML • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)